Cong Ma

89A, Harding St, Coburg, VIC3058 | 0466592676 | macong1989@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am seeking for a backend relevant programming position in which it is related to a server-side programming with high performance and sophisticated features. I am also an all-round player interested in Android development and Web development as well. I have expertise experience in C/C++ programming and sufficient Java/.Net development experience. Specifically, I have two years' experience in middleware development and Linux embedded development with networking programming. I also have excellent teamwork and communication skills as I worked on several projects which need team members to cooperate together.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Technology (Mar 2015 - Nov 2016)

RMIT University (GPA: 3.8)

Bachelor of Telecommunication Engineering (Sep 2008 – Jun 2012)

Nanjing University of Posts and Telecommunications

KEY SKILLS

- Programming: C (5/5), JAVA(5/5), C++ (4/5), C#(4/5), Perl (3.5/5)
- Web development: Net MVC Framework, HTML, JavaScript, jQuery, CSS, SQL
- Great understanding of software development process in both waterfall mode and agile mode
- Cloud Computing (AWS)
- Android application development
- Network Protocol: TCP/IP, UDP, FTP, HTTP
- POSIX threads programming
- Information retrieval technology includes clawing, indexing and ranking results
- Tools: Linux CMD, Eclipse, Visual Studio, Notepad++, TortoiseSVN / Git, Vim editor
- A great teamwork player

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

AWS based Android pedometer

An Android pedometer to collect your daily step counts and synchronise to the cloud

Prolific usage of Android SDK API

- Prolific usage of AWS Mobile SDKs
- AWS services including Cognito, Lambda, DynamoDB, IAM

Event Creator (Jul 2016 ~ Nov 2016)

An android application used to manage your daily event.

GitHub: https://github.com/TimThrill/EventCreater

- Prolific usage of Android SDK API
- Multithreading programming
- Google Map API
- · Background notification service

My Standards (Mar 2016 ~ Jun 2016)

A .Net web application used to manage tasks and position of employees in a largely decentralised structure. Features include delegate tasks to group members, attach documents to individual task and switch employees between different departments.

This project is part of RMIT final project and cooperated with ANZ.

- Developed a web application for ANZ
- Modern web application techniques such as
 - * .Net MVC framework, Entity framework
 - * jQuery, AJAX, RESTful API
 - bootstrap, CSS
 - * Microsoft SQL database
- Developed in a Scrum team

RMIT summer project (Dec 2015 – Jan 2016)

Location-based P2P network overlay for spatial keyword web search (Accepted by Australasian Database Conference 2016)

The project is a scholarship programme led by CS&IT school of RMIT.

- Simulated a mobile Ad-Hoc network by using OmNet++ (a mobile network simulation IDE with various C++ libs)
- Extracting, indexing, and ranking valuable information from large a data set such as Yelp
- This paper was acknowledged by ADC 2016

 Spatial Textual Top-k Search in Mobile Peer-to-Peer Networks http://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-3-319-46922-5_6

Information retrieval (Mar 2015 ~ Jul 2015)

I chose Information Retrieval as one of my specialisation course.

- Implemented core techniques such as ranking, inverted indexing and retrieval in an Information Retrieval system
- Java programming

A Chatting tool (2014)

Designed and developed a chat tool with teammates by using UDP/TCP protocol. The server side runs on Linux and uses EPOLL technical and client side uses MFC library.

- Socket programming
- UDP/TCP protocols
- Multithreading programming (POSIX)
- MFC, STL C++ library

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer | CertusNet Inc.

Jan 2014 to Jun 2014

CertusNet is a leading company in the industry of triple play streaming media regulatory monitoring and service assurance, the key technology and solution provider of IPTV end-to-end business monitor and service assurance in China, and the market share is more than 80%.

- Catch IP data packages from IPTV boxes and analyse user behaviours between the media box and backend server, especially by analysing the HTTP protocol or RTSP protocol. Provided valuable data to IPTV operators evaluating their quality of media services.
- Developed an HTTP protocol parsing interface. Improved my HTTP protocol understanding.
- Agile (Scrum) methodology. Keep the project on the right track in both business requirements and technique implementation.

Software Developer | Jiangsu FUJITSU Telecommunication and Technology (JFTT) Co., Ltd Jul 2012 to Dec 2013

Fujitsu Limited is a world-renowned International IT company. JFTT, with its excellent engineers who have high-class professional skills and rich development experience, provides design, building, implementation and technology support for IT system infrastructure, as well as a whole set of technical services that best satisfy customer needs.

• Developed middleware components for a large telecommunication system. Deployed the software in time with high quality.

- Developed an internal chatting tool by using a hybrid P2P topology. Improved P2P network knowledge.
- Developed a calling fee system (using JAVA, Spring Framework and SQL) with teammates.
 Improved teamwork skills.
- Maintained and redeveloped a file backup system (Using C and FTP protocol). Improved the understanding of Linux file systems and FTP protocols.
- Multithreading programming. Improved multithreading programming skills.
- Waterfall methodology. Excellent understanding of quality assurance in software development.

LANGUAGE

English: Working Proficiency certificated by IELTS (BAND 7)

Chinese: Native or Bilingual Proficiency

VOLUNTEERING

RMIT Lead program: Academic Mentor

I help students in the Computer Science and Information Technology stream, assisting them with study problems in those courses and provide one-on-one and small group support to students.

• RMIT Lead program: SSCC (Student-Staff Consultative Committees)

Student representatives are the voice of the student body in their study program. They consult with their peers to find out what program-related issues are of concern to them and present those issues for discussion at SSCC meetings, then provide feedback to the other students on the results of the consultations.

• RMIT Open Day Volunteer

Provide enthusiasm and passion to students to show our most hospitality. Give them the directional or any relative information about RMIT city campus.